Why do cats do that?
They're cute, they're lovable,
and judging by the 26 billions views
of over 2 million YouTube videos
of them pouncing /paʊns 猛扑/,
bouncing /baʊns 跳跃的/,
climbing,
cramming /kræm 塞满/,
stalking /stɔːk 潜近/,
clawing /klɔː 爪抓/,
chattering /ˈtʃætə 唠叨/,
and purring /pɜː 猫 呼噜声/,
one thing is certain:
cats are very entertaining /ˌentəˈteɪnɪŋ  令人愉快的/.
These somewhat strange feline /ˈfiːlaɪn  猫科动物/ behaviors,
both amusing /əˈmjuːz 使愉快/ and baffling /ˈbæfl 令人困惑/,
leave many of us asking,
"Why do cats do that?"
Throughout time, cats were simultaneously /ˌsɪmlˈteɪniəsli 同时地/
solitary /ˈsɒlətri 独居者/ predators /ˈpredətə/ of smaller animals
and prey for larger carnivores /ˈkɑːnɪˌvɔː 食肉动物/.
As both predator and prey,
survival of their species depended
on crucial /ˈkruːʃəl 至关重要的/ instinctual /in'stiŋktʃuəl 本能的/ behaviors
which we still observe in wild
and domestic cats today.
While the feline /ˈfiːlaɪn  猫科动物/ actions of your house cat
Grizmo might seem perplexing /pəˈpleksɪŋ 费解的/,
in the wild, these same behaviors,
naturally bred into cats
for millions of years,
would make Grizmo a super cat.
Enabled by their unique muscular /ˈmʌskjʊlə 肌肉的/ structure
and keen /kiːn 敏锐的/ balancing abilities,
cats climbed to high vantage /ˈvɑːntɪdʒ 优势/ points
to survey their territory
and spot prey in the wild.
Grizmo doesn't need these particular
skills to find and hunt down dinner
in her food bowl today,
but instinctually /ɪnˈstɪŋktʃʊəlɪ 本能地/, viewing the living room
from the top of the bookcase
is exactly what she has evolved to do.
As wild predators, cats are opportunistic /ˌɒpətjʊˈnɪstɪk 机会主义的/
and hunt whenever prey is available.
Since most cat prey are small,
cats in the wild needed to eat
many times each day,
and use a stalk /stɔːk 追踪/, pounce /paʊns 猛扑/, kill, eat
strategy to stay fed.
This is why Grizmo prefers to chase
and pounce on little toys
and eat small meals over the course
of the day and night.
Also, small prey tend to hide in tiny
spaces in their natural environments,
so one explanation /ˌɛkspləˈneɪʃən/ for Grizmo's propensity /prəˈpɛnsɪtɪ 习性/
to reach into containers and openings
is that she is compelled /kəmˈpɛl 强迫/ by
the same curiosity /ˌkjʊərɪˈɒsɪtɪ/
that helped ensure the continuation /kənˌtɪnjʊˈeɪʃən/ of
her species /ˈspiːʃiːz 物种/ for millions of years before.
In the wild, cats needed sharp claws
for climbing, hunting, and self-defense.
Sharpening their claws on nearby surfaces
kept them conditioned and ready,
helped stretch /strɛtʃ 有弹性的/ their back and leg muscles,
and relieve some stress, too.
So, it's not that Grizmo hates your couch /kaʊtʃ 长沙发椅/,
chair,
ottoman /ˈɒtəmən 软垫凳 土耳其人/,
pillows /ˈpɪləʊ 枕头/,
curtains /ˈkɜːtən 窗帘/,
and everything else
you put in her environment.
She's ripping /rɪp 撕/ these things to shreds
and keeping her claws in tip-top shape
because this is exactly what her ancestors
did in order to survive.
As animals that were preyed upon,
cats evolved to not get caught,
and in the wild, the cats that were
the best at avoiding predators thrived /θraɪv 繁荣/.
So at your house today,
Grizmo is an expert /ˈɛkspɜːt/
at squeezing /skwiːz 挤压/ into small spaces
and seeking out and hiding
in unconventional /ˌʌnkənˈvenʃənəl 非传统的/ spots.
It also explains why she prefers
a clean and odor/ˈəʊdə 气味 名声/-free litter box.
That's less likely to give away
her location to any predators
that may be sniffing around nearby.
Considering everything
we do know about cats,
it seems that one of their most
predominate /prɪˈdɒmɪˌneɪt 主宰/ behaviors
is still one of the most mysterious /mɪˈstɪərɪəs/.
Cats may purr for any number of reasons,
such as happiness,
stress,
and hunger.
But curiously,
the frequency of their purrs,
between 25 and 150 hertz /hɜːts HZ/,
is within a range that can promote /prəˈməʊt/
tissue regeneration /rɪˌdʒɛnəˈreɪʃən 再生/.
So while her purring makes Grizmo
an excellent /ˈɛksələnt 出色的/ nap /næp 小睡/ companion /kəmˈpænjən 同伴/,
it is also possible that her purr
is healing /hiːl 治愈/ her muscles and bones,
and maybe even yours, too.
They developed through time
as both solitary /ˈsɒlɪtərɪ 独居的/ predators
that hunted and killed to eat,
and stealthy /ˈstelθɪ 鬼鬼祟祟的/ prey that hid
and escaped to survive.
So cats today retain many
of the same instincts /instiŋkt 本能/
that allowed them to thrive in the wild
for millions of years.
This explains some of their seemingly
strange behaviors.
To them, our homes are their jungles.
But if this is the case,
in our own cat's eyes,
who are we?
Big, dumb, hairless cats competing with
them for resources?
Terribly stupid predators they're able
to outsmart /ˌaʊtˈsmɑːt 比…更聪明/ every day?
Or maybe they think we're the prey.